Guide to the Alison Jolly papers, circa 1919-2014
Jolly, Alison papers
- Series V. Audio-visual Material
  - Jean de Heaulme, prison Author: Alison Jolly Location: Berenty, 2000; tr-10822 (Box 21)
    Interview with Berenty Reserve owner about his imprisonment, research for Lords and Lemurs
  - Fenestina Author: Alison Jolly Fort Dauphin, 2000; tr-10823 (Box 21)
    Interview with AJ's housekeeper in 1960s, research for Lords and Lemurs
  - Jean de Heaulme Author: Alison Jolly Berenty, 2001; tr-10824 (Box 21)
    Research for Lords and Lemurs
  - Ramahatra I Author: Alison Jolly Antananarivo, 2000; tr-10825 (Box 21)
    Interview with Malagasy capital's one-time mayor, research for Lords and Lemurs
  - Heurtebize Author: Alison Jolly Research for Lords and Lemurs, c2000; tr-10826 (Box 21)
  - Heurtebize-Valiotaky Author: Alison Jolly Research for Lords and Lemurs, c2000; tr-10827 (Box 21)
  - Valiotaky Author: Alison Jolly Research for Lords and Lemurs, c2000; tr-10828 (Box 21)
  - Students sing Tsaketraky Author: Alison Jolly Location: Research for Lords and Lemurs, 2000; tr-10829 (Box 21)
  - Genevieve, Jonah, Lahivano Author: Alison Jolly Location: Interview with Malagasy primatalogical students and researchers, research for Lords and Lemurs, 2000; tr-10830 (Box 21)
  - Funeral Author: Alison Jolly Research for Lords and Lemurs, 2000; tr-10831 (Box 21)
  - Jean de Heaulme Tape 2 Author: Alison Jolly Location: Interview with Berenty owner, research for Lords and Lemurs, 2000; tr-10832 (Box 21)
  - Chantal du Pray Author: Alison Jolly Interview to do with St Foy reserve in South Madagascar, research for Lords and Lemurs, 2000; tr-10833 (Box 21)
  - Chantal du Pray and Georges Author: Alison Jolly Location: Research for Lords and Lemurs, 2000; tr-10834 (Box 21)
  - Marcou Author: Alison Jolly Research for Lords and Lemurs, 2000; tr-10835 (Box 21)
  - Msrs Zedacco Author: Alison Jolly Research for Lords and Lemurs, 2001; tr-10836 (Box 21)
  - Leon Razobelina Author: Alison Jolly Interview with onetime Malagasy Minister, leading Malagasy conservationist, research for Lords and Lemurs, 2001; tr-10837 (Box 21)
  - Hanta Rasamimanana Author: Alison Jolly Interview with key Malagasy conservationist and colleague of Alison's, research for Lords and Lemurs, 2001; tr-10838 (Box 21)
  - Alison Richard Author: Alison Jolly Interview with American primatologist who works in Malagasy conservation, research for Lords and Lemurs, 2001; tr-10839 (Box 21)
  - Soaba Author: Alison Jolly Interview in Cornell, in French, research for Lords and Lemurs, 2000; tr-10840 (Box 21)
  - Special Madagascar Paul Getty Wildlife Prize for African Field Service Author: Voice of America Radio programme about Getty prize being given to Jean and Henri de Heaulme, owners of Berenty wildlife reserve, of $20,000, donated by Jane Goodall, herself recipient of former prize. Alison Jolly interviewed as part of the programme. In French. Rockefeller Institute, 1985; tr-10841 (Box 21)
  - The Washburn Lecture Author: Museum of Science Location: Recording of lecture on primate communication, by Alison Jolly, 1984; tr-10842 (Box 21)
  - Low scruffy, Berenty, Indri Perinet, Still Lake group Author: Alison Jolly Location: Lemur calls from two sites, 1986; tr-10843 (Box 21)
  - Malagasy music Author: Alison Jolly Malagasy music, unknown recording by Alison Jolly, c2000; tr-10844 (Box 21)
  - Lemur Catta Ranging Author: Alison Jolly Goodyear productions, 1984; F-1591 (Box 21)
  - "Lemur catta Ranging", Sept. 26, 1984; V-9025 (Box 26)
    Reel to reel tape; 4:30 minutes
  - "Lemur catta Ranging", Jan. 1987; V-9026 (Box 26)
    Reel to reel tape
  - Berenty Lemurs, N/A; V-9027 (Box 26)
  - Berenty Reserve - Madagascar: E. fulvus rufus Infanticide, Oct. 8, 1997; V-9028 (Box 26)
  - WOM/EEB 301: Primate and Human Socities Lecture, Feb. 27, 1997; V-9029 (Box 26)
  - Sue Savage-Rumbaugh: People and Bonobos of Wamba, N/A; V-9030 (Box 26)
  - MAD 94: Kid's Baby's Death and Rest., N/A; V-9031 (Box 26)
    "Slides all are to Danika"; "FEAY to Allison"
  - National Geographic Explorer: Jungle Spirits of Madagascar, Apr. 21, 1991; V-9032 (Box 26)
  - MAD 93: 1 of 2, N/A; V-9033 (Box 26)
    "FEAY - Mary andamp; Bruce"
  - MAD 93: 2 of 2, N/A; V-9034 (Box 26)
    "Feay"
  - Alison and the Lemurs, N/A; V-9035 (Box 26)
  - Rockefeller University, Alison Jolly - Horizon: Tropical Time Table, Feb. 13, 1985; V-9036 (Box 26)
    52 minutes
  - Madagascar: Rio Tinto, Jan. 12, 2006; V-9037 (Box 26)
    21:36 minutes
  - National Geographic Television: Lemur Rescue, c. Sept. 26, 2002; v-9038 (Box 26)
    Includes a typed letter from Charlotte Mangin at National Geographic; 24:30 minutes
  - Expedition to Madagascar, N/A; V-9039 (Box 26)
  - Seven Wonders of the World: Alison Jolly, N/A; V-9040 (Box 26)
    Christopher Sykes Productions; 29 minutes
  - Monkey in the Mirror: An Astonishing Reflection of Ourselves in the Live of Moneys and Apes, Feb. 2, 1995; V-9041 (Box 26)
    Produced by Karen Bass for The Natural World (BBC 2)
  - Émission N°271: Madagascar, Les Derniers Lémuriens, Nov. 26, 2000; V-9042 (Box 26)
    22 minutes
  - 1991 Earthwatch - Berenty / Madagascar Lemurs Team II, c. Dec. 17, 1991; V-9043 (Box 26)
    Includes a hand-written letter; approx. 22 minutes
  - Berenty Reserve - Sifara's, Oct. 1993; V-9044 (Box 26)
  - Monkey in the Mirror, c. Feb. 2, 1995; V-9045 (Box 26)
    Draft (?)
  - Koko and Alison Jolly, N/A; V-9046 (Box 26)
    © The Gorilla Foundation; 25 minutes
  - Partridge Films: Wild Horizons: "Sifakas", Jun. 26, 1996; V-9047 (Box 26)
    TCIF copy; 25:55 minutes
  - Nova ®: "The Great Wildlife Heist", Mar. 11, 1997; V-9048 (Box 26)
    Approx. 60 minutes
  - Activités du Comité Régional de Développement, 1999; V-9049 (Box 26)
  - Wildlife on One: Gangland Lemurs, Feb. 25, 2002; V-9050 (Box 26)
    BBC2 Repeat Tx Version
  - Lemurs of Berenty: Fragments of Behavior, Aug. 8, 2001; V-9051 (Box 26)
    Includes a typed letter
  - La Double Vie de Verónique / French Madagascar Tape, N/A; V-9052 (Box 26)
    First title is of a film by Polish director Krzysztof Kieślowski
  - Wildlife on One - Lemurs (Sunday), Feb. 24, 2002; V-9053 (Box 26)
  - WNET/Nature: Monkey in the Mirror #1303, Sept. 27, 1995; V-9054 (Box 26)
    TRK 1-Stereo Full Mix / TRK 2-Stereo M andamp; E
  - Princeton University: The Natural World - Spirits of the Forest, Jun. 23, 1988; V-9055 (Box 26)
    50 minutes
  - Wild World / Dance of the Sifaka, N/A; V-9056 (Box 26)
  - Partridge Films: Ring Tail Lemurs (Work in Progress), N/A; V-9057 (Box 26)
  - Ai; The Chimpanzee Mind, 1991; V-9058 (Box 26)
    Tetsuro Matsuzawa at the Primate Research Institute, Kyoto Univ.
  - Madagascar, N/A; V-9059 (Box 26)
    Includes three hand-written notes from Howard Wilson; 45 minutes
  - Madagascar: Selected Interview Segments Concerning Environment Issues, N/A; V-9060 (Box 26)
    60 minutes
  - Partridge Films: A Lemur's Tale (WNET Version), N/A; V-9061 (Box 26)
  - Alison and the Lemurs - Real. Jérōme Auffret, N/A; V-9062 (Box 26)
    24:30 minutes
  - Life on Earth Series: The Primates, N/A; V-9063 (Box 26)
    30 minutes
  - The Madagascar Ilmente Project, Oct. 5, 2001; V-9064 (Box 26)
    15:30 minutes
  - Partridge Films: Wild Horizons 2: "Dance of the Sifaka", Aug. 1996; V-9065 (Box 26)
  - Nature Watch Lemurs, N/A; V-9066 (Box 26)
    25 minutes
  - Madagascar Vol. 1: Arrival - Berenty, Oct. 1993; V-9067 (Box 26)